RENATA SOARES

EN>PT (EU) Translator

Porto (Portugal) – +351 912 055 198 rsoares.translations@outlook.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

JUNE 2022 - CURRENTLY EN>PT (EU) FREELANCE TRANSLATOR

Currently collaborating with Deluxe Media, Zoo Digital, Iyuno-SDI,
 Visual Data Media Services, Bluelab (Gaming Localization),
 Lokilize, SMATIDIOM, TIPS, L10, among others.

JANUARY 2019 - MAY 2022 PROJECT MANAGER / IN-HOUSE

TRANSLATOR, WISDOM TRANSLATIONS

- Languages: Portuguese (EU) and English
- Project Manager: Responsible for managing the company's emails, drafting quotes, communicating with clients and freelance translators, and mentoring trainees.
- Translator: Responsible for translating and proofreading documents in several areas from English to Portuguese and viceversa.

2018 TRANSLATOR, JABA TRANSLATIONS

- Languages: Portuguese (EU) and English
- Internship as part of the Master's Degree in Translation and Language Services at the Faculty of Arts and Humanities of the University of Porto
- Translator/Reviewer



ABOUT ME:

Detailed-oriented Portuguese translator with a highly developed understanding of the English language and culture. Skilled in quickly and accurately translating written documents and subtitling. Excellent listening and communicating skills with an organized and systematic approach. Over five years of related expertise.

LANGUAGES:

Portuguese (EU)
Native

English Expert (C2)

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2016 - 2018

MASTER IN TRANSLATION AND LANGUAGE SERVICES, FACULTY OF ARTS AND HUMANITIES OF THE UNIVERSITY OF PORTO (PORTUGAL)

2013 - 2016

BACHELOR IN LANGUAGE SERVICES, FACULTY OF ARTS AND HUMANITIES OF THE UNIVERSITY OF PORTO (PORTUGAL)

KEY SKILLS

- Excellent Verbal, Non-Verbal, and Written Communication
- Cultural Awareness & Intelligence
- Time Management & Multitasking
- Analysis & Research
- Self-Management & Self-Motivation
- Creative Writing Skills

DIGITAL SKILLS

- Proficient user of Microsoft Office
- CAT Tools (SDL Trados; MemoQ; Memsource; Subtitle Workshop; Subtitle Edit.)
- Project Management Software (Trello; Plunet; ClickUp.)